A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Correspondence of Sidney Jones FA523
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Correspondence of Sidney Jones
1983-1985
Rockefeller Archive Center
Jones, Sidney, 1952-
Ford Foundation
FA523
1.31 Cubic Feet 1 standard record storage box.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Chronological
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence.
Biographical / Historical
Sidney Jones is a policy analyst with expertise on security and terrorism in Indonesia and Southeast Asia. From 1977 to 1984, Jones worked at the Ford Foundation. She joined the Foundation as an Assistant to the Representative in the Asia and the Pacific, Indonesia Program. She then became a Program Officer, and after a change in the Foundation's program structure, she was moved into the Developing Country Programs where she stayed until she left the Foundation in 1984.
Jones' post-Ford Foundation career has included positions in nonprofits in London, New York City, and Jakarta. She worked at Amnesty International in London as an Indonesia-Philippines-Pacific researcher, Human Rights Watch in New York City as Asia director, and the International Crisis Group in Jakarta as Southeast Asia project director and then senior advisor for the Asia program. After leaving the International Crisis Group, Jones became Director for the Institute for Policy Analysis of Conflict which is also based in Jakarta.
Jones earned a B.A. and M.A. from the University of Pennsylvania and received an honorary doctorate from The New School.
- 1983 Alpha A-L (Box 1)
- 1983 Alpha M-Z (Box 1)
- Apr-May 1983, 1983 April-May (Box 1)
- Jun-Jul 1983, 1983 June-July (Box 1)
- Aug-Sep 1983, 1983 August-September (Box 1)
- Oct-Dec 1983, 1983 October-December (Box 1)
- Jan-Feb 1984, 1984 January-February (Box 1)
- Mar-Apr 1984, 1984 March-April (Box 1)
- May-Jun 1984, 1984 May-June (Box 1)
- Jul-Aug 1984, 1984 July-August (Box 1)
- Sep-Oct 1984, 1984 September-October (Box 1)
- Nov 1984-Jan 1985, 1984 November-1985 January (Box 1)